He doesn't just talk to the animals!
Doctor Dolittle is a comedy, family, fantasy film directed by Betty Thomas.
A successful physician and devoted family man, John Dolittle seems to have the world by the tail, until a long suppressed
talent he possessed as a child, the ability to communicate with animals is suddenly reawakened with a vengeance!
Now every creature within squawking distance wants the good doctor's advice,
unleashing an outrageous chain of events that turns his world upside down!
Dr. John Dolittle, played by Eddie Murphy.
Archer Dolittle, played by Ossie Davis.
Dr. Mark Weller, played by Oliver Platt.
Calloway, played by Peter Boyle.
Dr. Gene Reiss, played by Richard Schiff.
Lisa, played by Kristen Wilson.
Dolittle is a 1998 American fantasy comedy film directed by Betty Thomas, written by Larry Levin and Nat
Mauldin, and starring Eddie Murphy in the title role, along with Ossie Davis and Oliver Platt.
The film is loosely based on the series of children's stories by Hugh Lofting.
Dolittle received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office
success, grossing $294 million against a $72 million budget.
The film's success generated a theatrical sequel, Dr.
Dolittle 2 (2001), and three films released direct to video: Dr.
Dolittle 3 (2006), Dr.
Dolittle: Tail to the Chief (2008), and Dr.
Dolittle: Million Dollar Mutts (2009).
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, tiger, san
francisco, california, veterinarian, monkey.
The tone is lighthearted.